<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<SPDXLicenseCollection xmlns="http://www.spdx.org/license">
	<exception licenseId="bacula-exception"
		name="Bacula exception to AGPL 3.0"
		listVersionAdded="3.20">
		
		<text>
			<p>
			Last revision: 21 May 2017
			</p>
			<p>
			Bacula is licensed under the GNU Affero General Public License, version
			3.0 as published by the Free Software Foundation, Inc. ("AGPLv3").
			</p>
			<p>
			Additional Terms on the work licensed herein, pursuant to Section 7 of
			Affero General Public License are as follows:
			</p>
			<p>
			  1. The name Bacula is a registered trademark of Kern Sibbald, and Kern
			     Sibbald hereby declines to grant a trademark license to "Bacula"
			     pursuant to AGPLv3, Section 7(e) without a separate agreement with Kern
			     Sibbald.
			</p>
			<p>
			  2. Pursuant to AGPLv3, Section 7(a), in addition to the warranty and
			     liability disclaimers already found in AGPLv3, the copyright holders
			     specifically disclaim any liability for accusations of patent
			     infringement by any third party.
			</p>
			<p>
			  3. Pursuant to AGPLv3, Section 7(b), the portions of the file AUTHORS that
			     are deemed to be specified reasonable legal notices and/or author
			     attributions shall be preserved in redistribution of source code and/or
			     modifications thereof. Furthermore, when the following notice appears in
			     a source code file, it must be preserved when source code is conveyed
			     and/or propagated:
			</p>
			<p>
			   Bacula(R) - The Network Backup Solution
			</p>
			<p>
			   Copyright (C) 2000-2017 Kern Sibbald
			</p>
			<p>
			   The original author of Bacula is Kern Sibbald, with contributions
			   from many others, a complete list can be found in the file AUTHORS.
			</p>
			<p>
			   You may use this file and others of this release according to the
			   license defined in the LICENSE file, which includes the Affero General
			   Public License, v3.0 ("AGPLv3") and some additional permissions and
			   terms pursuant to its AGPLv3 Section 7.
			</p>
			<p>
			   This notice must be preserved when any source code is conveyed
			   and/or propagated.
			</p>
			<p>
			   Bacula(R) is a registered trademark of Kern Sibbald.
			</p>
			<p>
			Additional Permissions on the work licensed herein, pursuant to Section 7 of
			AGPLv3 are as follows:
			</p>
			<p>
			1. As a special exception to the AGPLv3, the copyright holders give
			   permission to link the code of its release of Bacula with the OpenSSL
			   project's "OpenSSL" library (or with modified versions of it that use the
			   same license as the "OpenSSL" library), and distribute the linked
			   executables.  You must follow the requirements of AGPLv3 in all respects
			   for all of the code used other than "OpenSSL".
			</p>
			<p>
			2. As a special exception to the AGPLv3, the copyright holders give
			   permission to link the code of its release of the Bacula Win32 File daemon
			   with the Microsoft supplied Volume Shadow Copy (VSS) libraries and
			   distribute the linked executables.  You must follow the requirements of
			   the AGPLv3 in all respects for all of the code used other than for the
			   Microsoft VSS code.
			</p>
			<p>
			If you want to fork Bacula, please read the file LICENSE-FAQ.
			</p>
		</text>
	</exception>
</SPDXLicenseCollection>