<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<SPDXLicenseCollection xmlns="http://www.spdx.org/license">
	<exception licenseId="cups-apple-os-exception"
		name="CUPS Apple OS Exception to GPL and LGPL"
		listVersionAdded="3.20">
		
		<text>
			<p>
			In addition, as the copyright holder of CUPS, Apple Inc. grants
			the following special exceptions:
			</p>
			<p>
			     1. Apple Operating System Development License Exception;
			</p>
			<p>
				a. Software that is developed by any person or entity
				   for an Apple Operating System ("Apple OS-Developed
				   Software"), including but not limited to Apple and
				   third party printer drivers, filters, and backends
				   for an Apple Operating System, that is linked to the
				   CUPS imaging library or based on any sample filters
				   or backends provided with CUPS shall not be
				   considered to be a derivative work or collective work
				   based on the CUPS program and is exempt from the
				   mandatory source code release clauses of the GNU GPL.
				   You may therefore distribute linked combinations of
				   the CUPS imaging library with Apple OS-Developed
				   Software without releasing the source code of the
				   Apple OS-Developed Software. You may also use sample
				   filters and backends provided with CUPS to develop
				   Apple OS-Developed Software without releasing the
				   source code of the Apple OS-Developed Software.
			</p>
			<p>
				b. An Apple Operating System means any operating system
				   software developed and/or marketed by Apple Inc.,
				   including but not limited to all existing releases and
				   versions of Apple's Darwin, OS X, and OS X Server
				   products and all follow-on releases and future
				   versions thereof.
			</p>
			<p>
				c. This exception is only available for Apple
				   OS-Developed Software and does not apply to software
				   that is distributed for use on other operating
				   systems.
			</p>
			<p>
				d. All CUPS software that falls under this license
				   exception have the following text at the top of each
				   source file:
			</p>
			<p>
				     This file is subject to the Apple OS-Developed
				     Software exception.
			</p>
			<p>
			     2. OpenSSL Toolkit License Exception;
			</p>
			<p>
				a. Apple Inc. explicitly allows the compilation and
				   distribution of the CUPS software with the OpenSSL
				   Toolkit.
			</p>
			<p>
			No developer is required to provide these exceptions in a
			derived work.
			</p>
		</text>
	</exception>
</SPDXLicenseCollection>