<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<SPDXLicenseCollection xmlns="http://www.spdx.org/license">
	<exception licenseId="libwebsockets-exception"
		name="libwebsockets exception to LGPL 2.1"
		listVersionAdded="3.20">
		
		<text>
			<p>
			Libwebsockets and included programs are provided under the terms of the GNU
			Library General Public License (LGPL) 2.1, with the following exceptions:
			</p>
			<p>
			1) Any reference, whether in these modifications or in the GNU
			Library General Public License 2.1, to this License, these terms, the
			GNU Lesser Public License,  GNU Library General Public License, LGPL, or
			any similar reference shall refer to the GNU Library General Public
			License 2.1 as modified by these paragraphs 1) through 4).
			</p>
			<p>
			2) Static linking of programs with the libwebsockets library does not
			constitute a derivative work and does not require the author to provide 
			source code for the program, use the shared libwebsockets libraries, or
			link their program against a user-supplied version of libwebsockets.
			</p>
			<p>
			If you link the program to a modified version of libwebsockets, then the
			changes to libwebsockets must be provided under the terms of the LGPL in
			sections 1, 2, and 4.
			</p>
			<p>
			3) You do not have to provide a copy of the libwebsockets license with
			programs that are linked to the libwebsockets library, nor do you have to
			identify the libwebsockets license in your program or documentation as
			required by section 6 of the LGPL.
			</p>
			<p>
			However, programs must still identify their use of libwebsockets. The
			following example statement can be included in user documentation to
			satisfy this requirement:
			</p>
			<p>
			"[program] is based in part on the work of the libwebsockets  project
			(https://libwebsockets.org)"
			</p>
			<p>
			4) Some sources included have their own, more liberal licenses, or options
			to get original sources with the liberal terms.
			</p>
			<p>
			Original liberal license retained
			</p>
			<p>
			  - lib/sha-1.c         - 3-clause BSD license retained, link to original
			  - win32port/zlib      - ZLIB license (see zlib.h)
			  - lib/mbedtls_wrapper - Apache 2.0 (only built if linked against mbedtls)
			</p>
			<p>
			Relicensed to libwebsocket license
			</p>
			<p>
			  - lib/base64-decode.c - relicensed to LGPL2.1+SLE, link to original
			  - lib/daemonize.c     - relicensed from Public Domain to LGPL2.1+SLE,
			                          link to original Public Domain version
			</p>
			<p>
			Public Domain (CC-zero) to simplify reuse
			</p>
			<p>
			  - test-apps/*.c
			  - test-apps/*.h
			  - lwsws/*
			</p>
			<p>
			------ end of exceptions
			</p>
		</text>
	</exception>
</SPDXLicenseCollection>