<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<SPDXLicenseCollection xmlns="http://www.spdx.org/license">
	<license licenseId="blitz-artistic"
		name="Blitz++ Artistic License"
		isOsiApproved="false"
		listVersionAdded="3.20">
		
		<crossRefs>
			
			<crossRef>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/blitzpp/blitz/e3c973d68e5ee17aec779bf9711b38fd4afc355f/LICENSE</crossRef>
			
		</crossRefs>
		
		<text>
			<p>
			The `Blitz++ Artistic License'
			(with thanks and apologies to authors of the Perl Artistic License)
			</p>
			<p>
			Preamble
			</p>
			<p>
			The intent of this document is to state the conditions under which 
			Blitz++ may be copied, such that the authors maintains some
			semblance of artistic control over the development of the package,
			while giving the users of the package the right to use and
			distribute Blitz++ in a more-or-less customary fashion, plus the
			right to make reasonable modifications.
			</p>
			<p>
			Definitions
			</p>
			<p>
			`Library' refers to the collection of files distributed by the
			Copyright Holder, and derivatives of that collection of files
			created through textual modification.
			</p>
			<p>
			`Standard Version' refers to such a Library if it has not been
			modified, or has been modified in accordance with the wishes of the
			Copyright Holder as specified below.
			</p>
			<p>
			Copyright Holder' is whoever is named in the copyright or
			copyrights for the package.
			</p>
			<p>
			`You' is you, if you're thinking about copying, modifying or
			distributing this Library.
			</p>
			<p>
			`Freely Available' means that no fee is charged for the item.
			It also means that recipients of the item may redistribute it 
			under the same conditions they received it.
			</p>
			<p>
			``Reasonable copying fee'' is whatever you can justify on the basis
			of media cost, duplication charges, time of people involved, and so
			on. (You will not be required to justify it to the Copyright Holder,
			but only to the computing community at large as a market that must
			bear the fee.)
			</p>
			<p>
			1. You may make and give away verbatim copies of the 
			Standard Version of this Library without restriction, provided that
			you duplicate all of the original copyright notices, this license,
			and associated disclaimers. 
			</p>
			<p>
			2. The Standard Version of the Library may be distributed as part
			of a collection of software, provided no more than a reasonable
			copying fee is charged for the software collection.
			</p>
			<p>
			3. You may apply bug fixes, portability fixes and other modifications
			derived from the Public Domain or from the Copyright Holder. A
			Library modified in such a way shall still be considered the
			Standard Version.
			</p>
			<p>
			4. You may otherwise modify your copy of this Library in any way,
			provided that you insert a prominent notice in each changed file
			stating how and when you changed that file, and provided that you do
			at least ONE of the following:
			</p>
			<p>
			a. place your modifications in the Public Domain or otherwise
			make them Freely Available, such as by posting said
			modifications to the Blitz++ development list, 
			and allowing the Copyright Holder to include
			your modifications in the Standard Version of the Library.
			</p>
			<p>
			b. use the modified Library only within your corporation or
			organization. 
			</p>
			<p>
			c. make other distribution arrangements with the Copyright
			Holder.
			</p>
			<p>
			5. You may distribute programs which use this Library
			in object code or executable form without restriction.
			</p>
			<p>
			6. Any object code generated as a result of using this Library 
			does not fall under the copyright of this Library, but
			belongs to whomever generated it, and may be sold commercially.
			</p>
			<p>
			7. The name of the Copyright Holder or the Library may not be used to 
			endorse or promote products derived from this software without 
			specific prior written permission.
			</p>
			<p>
			8. THIS PACKAGE IS PROVIDED `AS IS' AND WITHOUT ANY EXPRESS OR
			IMPLIED WARRANTIES, INCLUDING, WITHOUT LIMITATION, THE IMPLIED
			WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTIBILITY AND FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE.
			</p>
		</text>
	</license>
</SPDXLicenseCollection>