<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<SPDXLicenseCollection xmlns="http://www.spdx.org/license">
	<license licenseId="hugo"
		name="Hugo License"
		isOsiApproved="false"
		listVersionAdded="3.20">
		
		<text>
			<p>
			HUGO LICENSE - December 19, 2003
			--------------------------------
			</p>
			<p>
			Copyright (c) 2003 by Kent Tessman
			The General Coffee Company Film Productions
			</p>
			<p>
			
			1.   Definitions
			</p>
			<p>
			"Copyright Holder" refers to Kent Tessman.
			</p>
			<p>
			"End User" refers to a user of the Software.
			</p>
			<p>
			"End User Program" refers to a computer program created by an End
			User, written using the Hugo Programming Language and compiled using
			the Hugo Compiler.
			</p>
			<p>
			"Hugo" refers to the Hugo Interactive Fiction Development System, created
			by the Copyright Holder.
			</p>
			<p>
			"Hugo Programming Language" refers to the Hugo programming language and
			its characteristic syntax.
			</p>
			<p>
			"Hugo Source Code" refers to the human-readable source code of the
			Software.
			</p>
			<p>
			"License" refers to this license.
			</p>
			<p>
			"Software" refers to the Hugo Compiler, the Hugo Engine, the Hugo
			Debugger, the Hugo Library, and any other related programs or files.
			</p>
			<p>
			
			2.   Ownership and Grant of Rights
			</p>
			<p>
			2.1  Hugo is the property of the Copyright Holder.  The Copyright Holder
			retains its copyright in the Software, without limitation.
			</p>
			<p>
			2.2  The Copyright Holder grants to the End User the right to use the
			Software solely for the purposes of:
			</p>
			<p>
			     (a) running programs created with the Software; and
			</p>
			<p>
			     (b) creating End User Programs.
			</p>
			<p>
			2.3  End User Programs are the property of the End User.
			</p>
			<p>
			
			3.   Provision of the Hugo Source Code
			</p>
			<p>
			3.1  The Copyright Holder has made available to the End User the Hugo
			Source Code for the purposes of:
			</p>
			<p>
			     (a) porting the Software to operating systems for which the
			         Software is not yet available; and
			</p>
			<p>
			     (b) investigating the functionality of the Software.
			</p>
			<p>
			3.2  In no way does the Copyright Holder's act of making available the
			Hugo Source code reduce or otherwise affect in any way its rights in
			the Hugo Source Code.
			</p>
			<p>
			
			4.   Modification and Distribution
			</p>
			<p>
			4.1  Distribution of the Software or the Hugo Source Code, in whole or
			in part, in a modified form without the express written consent of the
			Copyright Holder is prohibited.
			</p>
			<p>
			4.2  Distribution of the Software or the Hugo Source Code, in whole or
			in part, for profit or other commercial intent or monetary transaction
			without the express written consent of the Copyright Holder is
			prohibited.
			</p>
			<p>
			4.3  This License must be distributed with any distribution of the 
			Software or the Hugo Source Code.
			</p>
			<p>
			
			5.   Warranty
			</p>
			<p>
			The Software and the Hugo Source Code are provided "as is" without
			warranty of any kind, either expressed or implied, including but not
			limited to the implied warranties of merchantability and fitness for a
			particular purpose.  In no event shall the Copyright Holder or The 
			General Coffee Company Film Productions or any other related or
			unrelated party be liable to the End User or any other individual or
			entity for damages arising out of the use or inability to use these or
			other programs.  Use of the Software indicates acceptance of these
			terms.
			</p>
		</text>
	</license>
</SPDXLicenseCollection>