<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<SPDXLicenseCollection xmlns="http://www.spdx.org/license">
	<license licenseId="lzma-sdk-2008"
		name="LZMA SDK 2008"
		isOsiApproved="false"
		listVersionAdded="3.20">
		
		<text>
			<p>
			LZMA SDK provides the documentation, samples, header files, libraries, 
			and tools you need to develop applications that use LZMA compression.
			</p>
			<p>
			LICENSE
			-------
			</p>
			<p>
			LZMA SDK is available under any of the following licenses:
			</p>
			<p>
			1) GNU Lesser General Public License (GNU LGPL)
			2) Common Public License (CPL)
			3) Common Development and Distribution License (CDDL) Version 1.0 
			4) Simplified license for unmodified code (read SPECIAL EXCEPTION) 
			</p>
			<p>
			It means that you can select one of these options and follow rules of that license.
			</p>
			<p>
			1,2,3) GNU LGPL, CPL and CDDL licenses are classified as 
			 - "Free software licenses" at http://www.gnu.org/ 
			 - "OSI-approved" at http://www.opensource.org/
			</p>
			<p>
			4) Simplified license for unmodified code (read SPECIAL EXCEPTION) 
			</p>
			<p>
			Igor Pavlov, as the author of this code, expressly permits you 
			to statically or dynamically link your code (or bind by name) 
			to the files from LZMA SDK. 
			</p>
			<p>
			SPECIAL EXCEPTION allows you to use LZMA SDK in applications with closed code, 
			while you keep LZMA SDK code unmodified.
			</p>
			<p>
			SPECIAL EXCEPTION #2: Igor Pavlov, as the author of this code, expressly permits 
			you to use this code under the same terms and conditions contained in the License 
			Agreement you have for any previous version of LZMA SDK developed by Igor Pavlov.
			</p>
			<p>
			SPECIAL EXCEPTION #2 allows owners of proprietary licenses to use latest version 
			of LZMA SDK as update for previous versions.
			</p>
			<p>
			Some files in LZMA SDK are placed in public domain.
			Some of these "public domain" files:
			C\Types.h,
			C\LzmaLib.*
			C\LzmaLibUtil.*
			LzmaAlone.cpp, 
			LzmaAlone.cs, 
			LzmaAlone.java
			</p>
			<p>
			So you can change them as you want and use "SPECIAL EXCEPTION" 
			for other unmodified files. For example, you can edit C\Types.h to solve some 
			compatibility problems with your compiler.
			</p>
			<p>
			-----
			</p>
			<p>
			You should have received a copy of the GNU Lesser General Public
			License along with this library; if not, write to the Free Software
			Foundation, Inc., 59 Temple Place, Suite 330, Boston, MA  02111-1307  USA
			</p>
			<p>
			You should have received a copy of the Common Public License
			along with this library.
			</p>
			<p>
			You should have received a copy of the Common Development and Distribution 
			License Version 1.0 along with this library.
			</p>
		</text>
	</license>
</SPDXLicenseCollection>