<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<SPDXLicenseCollection xmlns="http://www.spdx.org/license">
	<license licenseId="merit-network-derivative"
		name="Merit Network Derivative Works License"
		isOsiApproved="false"
		listVersionAdded="3.20">
		
		<text>
			<p>
			Permission to use, copy, and modify this software and its documentation 
			for any purpose and without fee is hereby granted, provided: 
			</p>
			<p>
			1) that the above copyright notice and this permission notice appear in all
			   copies of the software and derivative works or modified versions thereof, 
			</p>
			<p>
			2) that both the copyright notice and this permission and disclaimer notice 
			   appear in all supporting documentation, and 
			</p>
			<p>
			3) that all derivative works made from this material are returned to the
			   Regents of the University of Michigan and Merit Network, Inc. with
			   permission to copy, to display, to distribute, and to make derivative
			   works from the provided material in whole or in part for any purpose.
			</p>
			<p>
			Users of this code are requested to notify Merit Network, Inc. of such use
			by sending email to aaa-admin@merit.edu
			</p>
			<p>
			Please also use aaa-admin@merit.edu to inform Merit Network, Inc of any
			derivative works.
			</p>
			<p>
			Distribution of this software or derivative works or the associated
			documentation is not allowed without an additional license.
			</p>
			<p>
			Licenses for other uses are available on an individually negotiated
			basis.  Contact aaa-license@merit.edu for more information.
			</p>
			<p>
			THIS SOFTWARE IS PROVIDED "AS IS" WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY KIND, EITHER
			EXPRESS OR IMPLIED, INCLUDING WITHOUT LIMITATION WARRANTIES OF
			MERCHANTABILITY AND FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE.  THE REGENTS OF THE
			UNIVERSITY OF MICHIGAN AND MERIT NETWORK, INC. DO NOT WARRANT THAT THE
			FUNCTIONS CONTAINED IN THE SOFTWARE WILL MEET LICENSEE'S REQUIREMENTS OR
			THAT OPERATION WILL BE UNINTERRUPTED OR ERROR FREE.  The Regents of the
			University of Michigan and Merit Network, Inc. shall not be liable for any
			special, indirect, incidental or consequential damages with respect to any
			claim by Licensee or any third party arising from use of the software.
			</p>
		</text>
	</license>
</SPDXLicenseCollection>