<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<SPDXLicenseCollection xmlns="http://www.spdx.org/license">
	<license licenseId="simpl-1.1"
		name="Simple Public License Version 1.1"
		isOsiApproved="false"
		listVersionAdded="3.20">
		
		<text>
			<p>
			SIMPLE PUBLIC LICENSE                        VERSION 1.1   2003-01-21
			</p>
			<p>
			Copyright (c) The Analysis and Solutions Company
			http://www.analysisandsolutions.com/
			</p>
			<p>
			1.  Permission to use, copy, modify, and distribute this software and
			its documentation, with or without modification, for any purpose and
			without fee or royalty is hereby granted, provided that you include
			the following on ALL copies of the software and documentation or
			portions thereof, including modifications, that you make:
			</p>
			<p>
			    a.  The full text of this license in a location viewable to users
			    of the redistributed or derivative work.
			</p>
			<p>
			    b.  Notice of any changes or modifications to the files,
			    including the date changes were made.
			</p>
			<p>
			2.  The name, servicemarks and trademarks of the copyright holders
			may NOT be used in advertising or publicity pertaining to the
			software without specific, written prior permission.
			</p>
			<p>
			3.  Title to copyright in this software and any associated
			documentation will at all times remain with copyright holders.
			</p>
			<p>
			4.  THIS SOFTWARE AND DOCUMENTATION IS PROVIDED "AS IS," AND
			COPYRIGHT HOLDERS MAKE NO REPRESENTATIONS OR WARRANTIES, EXPRESS OR
			IMPLIED, INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO, WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY
			OR FITNESS FOR ANY PARTICULAR PURPOSE OR THAT THE USE OF THE SOFTWARE
			OR DOCUMENTATION WILL NOT INFRINGE ANY THIRD PARTY PATENTS,
			COPYRIGHTS, TRADEMARKS OR OTHER RIGHTS.
			</p>
			<p>
			5.  COPYRIGHT HOLDERS WILL NOT BE LIABLE FOR ANY DAMAGES, INCLUDING
			BUT NOT LIMITED TO, DIRECT, INDIRECT, SPECIAL OR CONSEQUENTIAL,
			ARISING OUT OF ANY USE OF THE SOFTWARE OR DOCUMENTATION.
			</p>
		</text>
	</license>
</SPDXLicenseCollection>